Carine Nzeyimana

West Bromwich, Birmingham, UK Email: nzevimac@gmail.com | Mobile: 07849272353

Personal Profile

Agile and highly creative Analyst with over 3 years practical experience and knowledge across the data pipeline, from data modelling & database querying to insights reporting & visualisation. With advanced PowerBI and SQL skills, I am looking to join a data-driven team to develop my skills further and produce strong analysis and visualisations that drive strategic decisions.

Employment History

BI Analyst March 2022 – Present

Acorn Insurance, Birmingham

Design and develop reporting and insight solutions, with emphasis in PowerBI and SQL for data transformation and delivering self-serve dashboards tailored to management requirements.

- Overseeing data visualisation developments for existing and new reporting becoming Power BI SME within 4 months of commencing the role and improving report utilisation by 25% across Personal Injury and Credit Hire departments.
- Providing quarterly KPI analysis and recommendations to the Head of Claims
 Strategy to reduce exposure to risk and indemnity spend.
- Training and supporting colleagues within the team and wider business by facilitating 1-1/group PowerBi training, peer code reviews and data validation across SSIS and SSMS. With additional training materials and manuals for long-term support.
- Processing ad-hoc requests and recurring automated reports for the wider business.

Data Analyst

October 2021 – March 2022

AFH Wealth Management, Birmingham

Created and developed reports and automation processes for senior management and external stakeholders, whilst auditing data quality and performing root cause analysis for rectification.

- Delivering scheduled and ad-hoc MI using excel and Power BI for use of management and clients.
- Collaborating with the management team for MI queries and requests.
- Identifying and highlighting data trends within company MI and escalating to appropriate departments.
- Developing and automating reporting processes using macros and power query.

Pricing Analyst (Apprentice)Nectere, Birmingham

March 2021 - October 2021

Responsible for delivering strategic pricing solutions to the commercial and marketing department by analysing competitors, market trends and sales using advanced SQL and Excel to pull essential project data and reports.

- Created pricing models and structures using excel (sumifs, xlookups, index match), VBA and calculated fields to aid marketing in pricing campaigns.
- Priced over 5000 products for publications achieved 15% increase in profit margins and improved competitiveness by 35% for end of Q2.
- Generated £5000 rebate owed by investigating supplier and brand contracts and categorising transaction data.
- Completed data analysis modules including data lifecycle, structure, cleansing and manipulating and linking.

Education & Qualifications

BSc (Hons) Economics and Politics (2:1)

2015 - 2019

Aston University, Birmingham

Additional Oversea Study (3rd year of degree programme)

2018

Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong

• **Courses:** Economics of Behavioural Finance (B), Public Finance (B) and Mandarin (A).

Skills Profile

- Proficient in SQL, SSIS, SSMS, Visual Studio, MS Azure, PowerBI (DAX and M Query) and Excel.
- Excellent written and verbal communication skills in clearly explaining complex models, reports and analysis to groups, senior management and external stakeholders.
- Highly adaptable to organisational structure, systems and processes. Particularly enhanced in current role.
- Strong attention to detail in analytical assessments; experience in developing and maintaining high quality reports and delivering presentations to stakeholders.

Achievements and Awards

- Nominated for Midlands Women in Tech Awards 2021 within 3 months of Apprenticeship.
- Achieved first place at 2018 UCL Young Investment Banker Weekend for best team investment strategy.
- Awarded 2015 Economics student of the year.